# JESSICA CLAIRE

resumesample@example

(555) 432-1000,

Montgomery Street, San Francisco, CA 94105

• :

A

A

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Plant Engineer experienced in overseeing plant systems' operations, maintenance, modifications and improvements. Extensive management of capital projects from inception through operational acceptance. Experienced in environmental compliance including storm water, hazardous waste, wastewater, etc. Self-motivated with ability to interpret and fulfill company goals.

#### **SKILLS**

- Lean principles knowledge
- Team leadership
- Works well in diverse team environment
- · Strong decision maker
- AutoCAD proficient
- Complex problem solvingMultidisciplinary exposure

#### EDUCATION

California State University Long Beach, CA •  $\hat{a} \in \hat{a} \in \hat{a}$ 

**BS:** Mechanical Engineering - C Mechanical Engineering

#### WORK HISTORY

Corning - Maintenance & Process Engineering Manager

Corning, NY, • • 2012 - Current

- Responsible for managing the maintenance and process engineering functions in support of company production and quality goals.
- Sourced and installed vacuum pump system to relieve plastic pellet supply bottleneck.
- Effort resulted in optimum levels of PPG pellets to meet our increased demands.
- Resolved process issue with web forming belt that would stop production process, enabling production to run difficult product with minimal stoppages.
- Supported all OE KPI efforts on a daily basis by monitoring and correcting data input by floor supervisors.
- Efforts have resulted in accurate measurement of OE.

Sonoco Products Co, - Toll House Maintenance Manager Pittsfield, ME, • • 2006 - 2011

- Managed Toll House maintenance department (17 team members).
- Implemented clear departmental goals and expectations for each team member and supervisor creating a focused approach to problem solving and accountability.
- Led Total Performance Management (TPM) Pillar Team in launching maintenance work groups resulting in MTBF (Mean Time Between Failure) increase and 43% technical downtime reduction.
- Spearheaded plant efforts to perform root cause analysis, coaching and leading BDA (Breakdown Analysis) teams focusing on eradication of technical stoppages.
- Ensured Preventive Maintenance remained foundational throughout time as manager resulting in PM completion rates above 95%.
- Coordinated various design improvements including conveyor belt modification, dough cutter enhancement, both resulting in eradication of chronic technical issues.

# Dart Container Of Michigan - Facilities Engineer

Grand Prairie, TX, • • 2003 - 2006

- Managed highly skilled craftsmen in the implementation of plant projects.
- Oversaw all plant support equipment operations, coordinating preventive maintenance work with outside contractors.
- Led maintenance team in the daily and monthly efforts at downtime minimization.
- Headed all efforts to complete maintenance and environmental ALCOA audit requirements.
- Efforts resulted in a clear passing score for all audit items under my responsibility.
- Spearheaded team to close all open environmental non-compliance findings resulting in 100% closure by 12/2003.
- · Plant business declined and closed doors in January 2007.

# Ashland Global Inc. - Plant Manager

Hopewell, VA, • • 1998 - 2002

- Led and managed all plant operations and personnel to achieve corporate goals.
- Maintained yearly plant budget (\$2M) well within limits for four consecutive years.
- Implemented plant cost savings efforts resulting in \$98,000 operating expense savings.
- Established daily production team meetings resulting in effective coordination of planning, scheduling and shipping, minimizing "stock outs" for major customers.
- Initiated weekly plant wide safety meetings resulting in elevated safety awareness.
- Launched production quality checks resulting in 75% issue reduction.

# MARTIN COLOR-FI - Project Engineer

City, STATE, • • 1995 - 1998

- Supervised team of seven construction craftsmen in process and equipment improvements resulting in increased plant efficiency.
- Managed capital project resulting in successful launch of new multimillion-dollar fiber production equipment.

- Duties included specifying new drain system, drawing scaled layout of all equipment using AutoCAD, supervising all pre-work and installation of all equipment.
- Designed recirculating chemical feed system resulting in increased productivity.
- Designed 1-ton bridge crane hoist.

  Calculated beam size for load and span, drew blueprint with AutoCAD, developed bill of materials, and directed fabrication through completion.

# WESTINGHOUSE HANFORD - Plant/Project Engineer

City, STATE, • • 1992 - 1995

- Directed work team of engineers and multi-functional craftsmen in testing and successful acceptance of a computer integrated control system for closed loop
- cooling of plant equipment, meeting the Department of Energy deadlines.

  Managed compressor, vacuum and cooling systems with less than 5% equipment down time.
- Authored and performed operational test procedures, coordinating contractor and maintenance personnel tasks.
- Originated equipment and process operating procedures giving clear direction to operators.
- Developed calibration procedures for process instruments (magnetic flow meters, etc.) Lead maintenance team in troubleshooting plant equipment resulting in minimal downtime.

## **SKILLS**

approach, AutoCAD, budget, calibration, coaching, direction, doors, functional, drawing, layout, managing, materials, meetings, 98, Performance Management, personnel, problem solving, process engineering, quality, safety, scheduling, shipping, supervisor, supervising, troubleshooting

## ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

ADDITIONAL RELEVANT EXPERIENCE Captain - United States Air Force Intelligence Officer, 1987-1991